A Guide to the Virginia Credit Union League records, 1946-1949
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Virginia Credit Union League records, 1946-1949
The Library of Virginia
31833
.45 cu. ft., 1 box
Virginia Credit Union League
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Mildred M. Crooks, Central Records Department, Office of the Comptroller, Richmond, Virginia, 1980.
Biographical Information
The Virginia Credit Union League was organized 26 November 1934 to help credit unions in the state work together. Today the league's headquarters are located in Lynchburg, Virginia.
Scope and Content
Records, 1946-1949, of the Virginia Credit Union League, consisting of correspondence, accounts, by-laws, certificates, minutes; financial reports; annual information from individual member credit unions; papers concerning credit union legislation in the Virginia general assembly; constitution and by-laws of the Richmond chapter of the league; papers concerning credit unions and regulations; letter and pamphlet from the Federal Security Agency concerning credit unions; forms and form letters; publications of member credit unions and of other states' leagues; papers of the Credit Union National Association (CUNA); copies of CUNA's association magazine The Bridge; papers concerning the CUNA Mutual Insurance Society; CUNA Organization and Education News newsletter; papers relating to the CUNA supply cooperative; CUNA membership drive packet; magazines; supply catalogs, advertisements, and miscellaneous papers.
Contents List
- Correspondence, 1946-1949. (Folder 1)
- Financial reports, >1947-1949. (Folder 2)
- Annual information forms, 1947. (Folder 3)
- Papers regarding Virginia House of Delegates bill no. 420, 1947-1948. (Folder 4)
- Richmond chapter of the Virginia Credit Union League constitution and by-laws, no date. (Folder 5)
- Statutes, interpretations of regulations, by-laws, and definitions, 1948. (Folder 6)
- Federal Security Agency, 1949. (Folder 7)
- Form letters and forms, 1948-1949. (Folder 8)
- Publications of Virginia Credit Union League members and of other state credit union leagues, 1947-1949. (Folder 9)
- Credit Union National Association (CUNA) papers, 1948. (Folder 10)
- CUNA magazine The Bridge, 1946-1948. (Folder 11)
- CUNA Mutual Insurance Society papers, 1948-1949. (Folder 12)
- CUNA newsletter Organization and Education News, 1948-1949. (Folder 13)
- CUNA supply cooperative, 1948. (Folder 14)
- CUNA membership drive packet, 1948. (Folder 15)
- Publications consisting of Our Abundant Forests, San Antonio Facts, Romantic San Antonio, The Motor Vehicle Messenger, Tax Administrators News, Virginia Highway Bulletin, The Commonwealth, Thrift, and The Insurance Index, 1947-1949. (Folder 16)
- Advertisements, supply catalogs, 1948. (Folder 17)
- Miscellaneous papers, no date. (Folder 18)